https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Hi.
Ahoj.
Hey.
Čau.
Where's your dad?
Kde máš tátu?
He hasn't shown up all day.
Celý den se tu neukázal.
Gott invited him to a party.
Gott ho pozval na večírek.
He's moving to Karlstejn, throwing a farewell bash.
Stěhuje se na Karlštejn, pořádá rozlučku.
In the afternoon like this?
Takhle odpoledne?
They've been at it since morning.
Mají to už od rána.
Who would've thought even Gott knows that trick?
Kdo by to řekl, že ten trik zná i Gott?
Trick?
Trik?
Yeah, you invite people to a fake party, then tell them the movers bailed and your buddies haul everything for free.
No, pozveš lidi na falešný mejdan, pak jim řekneš, že stěhováci píchli a kámoši to odtáhaj za dara.
No way.
A to ne.
Dad went there in a white suit, it must be something classy.
Otec tam šel v bílém obleku, to bude něco nobl.
Beer, for God's sake.
Pivo pro boha.
What happened?
Co se stalo?
That Karel has such bad luck.
Ten Karel má ale smůlu.
The movers bailed, we were still there, otherwise he wouldn't have moved.
Stěhováci píchli, ještě jsme tam byli, jinak by se nepřestěhoval.
That Karel is a real class act, I'm telling you.
Ten Karel je stejně fórmát, to vám povím.
Yeah.
To jo.
I would've helped a friend for free, but he insisted on paying.
Já bych pomohl kamarádovi i zadarmo, ale on že ne.
Look what he gave me.
Hele, co mi dal.
A voucher for a free dinner at a French restaurant.
Poukaz na večeři zdarma ve francouzské restauraci.
Sorry, reflex.
Pardon, reflex.
Chez Blimbles?
Chez Blimbles?
Chez Blimbles, that's French.
Chez Blimbles, to je francouzsky.
French for what?
A francouzsky co?
At Blimble's.
U Blimble.
And what's a Blimble?
A co je to Blimble?
The owner, judging by the name, a Frenchman.
Majitel, podle jména Francouz.
I thought we could go there together when you have your name day.
Myslel jsem, že bysme tam mohli jít spolu, když budeš mít ten svátek.
I'm having a name day too.
Já budu mít taky svátek.
Sorry, there I go again.
Pardon, už zase.
How about Saturday?
Můžem třeba v sobotu?
Yeah, Saturday would work.
Jo, v sobotu by to šlo.
I'll shut up now.
Už mlčím.
I don't know, probably not.
Já nevím, spíš ne.
Why not?
A proč?
I'm starting a diet.
Začínám hubnout.
Iva, you just dieted recently.
Ivo, vždyť si hubla nedávno.
Well, I'm dieting again.
No tak hubnu znova, no.
Are you saying dinner is going to be carrots again?
To mě chceš říct, že k večeři bude zase mrkev?
Not carrots, they say they have too many carbs.
Mrkev ne, v ní prej spousta sacharidů.
Well, that's something.
Aspoň že tak.
But there'll be cabbage.
Ale bude kapusta.
If you want, you can have bread with it, you and Ozzak.
Jestli chcete, můžete si k ní s Ozzákem vzít chleba.
Sure, needing to diet is one thing, but why are you taking the whole family hostage?
Jo, to, že potřebuješ hubnout, je jedna věc, ale proč si bereš celou rodinu jako rukojmí?
Me, needing to lose weight?
Já, že potřebuju zhubnout?
You said it yourself.
Vždyť jsi to sama řekla.
Great, so my own father thinks I'm fat.
No tak to je výborný, můj vlastní otec si myslí, že jsem tlustá.
I didn't say that.
No to jsem neřekl.
But you're thinking it.
No ale myslíš si to.
Jesus, maybe just say something.
Ježišmarja, si možná tak řekni něco.
But just
Ale jen
And French cuisine is nothing but fat.
A francouzská kuchyně, to je samej tuk.
That wouldn't be good for you.
To by pro tebe nebylo moc dobrý.
Well, thanks a lot.
Tak vám teda pěkně děkuju.
Hey.
Zdar.
What's up, bro?
Co je, brácha?
Here we go again.
Už je to zas tady.
Iva's dieting.
Iva hubne.
Ivuska!
Ivuško!
Carrots?
Mrkev?
Cabbage.
Kapusta.
What is that?
Co to je?
That green stuff that looks like Jimi Hendrix.
Takový to zelený, co vypadá jako Jimi Hendrix.
Oh great.
No nazdar.
Ivuska, you don't need to lose weight.
Ivuško, ty přece hubnout nepotřebuješ.
Guys like girls who have something to grab onto.
A chlapi maj rádi holky, který je za co vzít.
And that's you, right?
A to ty séš, ne?
Did I say something?
Řekl jsem něco?
Because of you we'll have no bread tonight.
Kvůli tobě budeme večer bez chleba.
Then we need to get some somewhere else.
Tak se ho musíme dojít někde jinde.
So again, toads are poisonous.
Takže znova, ropuchy jsou jedovatý.
Bro, you can't believe everything people tell you.
Brácha, nesmíš věřit všemu, co ti lidi nakecaj.
Ozzak himself always offered me one.
Ozzák už vždycky mi sám jednu nabízel.
Good thing you didn't take it.
Dobře, že jsi si nevzal.
You would've felt sick.
Bylo by ti pak nějak blbno.
Don't worry, hang in there and I'll take you to a dinner you never dreamed of.
Neboj, vydrž a vezmu tě na večeři, o jaký se ti ani nesnilo.
A fancy restaurant.
Nobl restaurace.
And I'm paying.
A platím já.
Thanks, bro.
Díky, brácha.
Really, Tomas, you're so generous.
Fakt, Tomáši, ty seš tak velkorysej.
Simona?
Simona?
Yeah?
No?
You're not going.
Nejdeš.
Can you help me?
Můžeš mi pomoct?
Can't you wait till I unpack?
To nemůžeš počkat, až to vybalím.
I'm starting tomorrow morning.
Když já začínám už zítra ráno.
Alright then.
No tak jo.
But you have to walk by like you're just passing.
Ale musíš jít jenom jako náhodou okolo.
Yeah.
Jo.
And most importantly, act like a complete stranger.
A hlavně se tváříš jako úplně cizí člověk.
Can't you earn money for that swimsuit doing something you're actually good at?
To si na ty plavky nemůžeš vydělat něčím, co zvládáš?
There was nothing else available except handing out flyers.
Když ono kromě rozdávání letáků nic volného nebylo.
Alright then.
No tak jo.
You acted too much like a stranger.
Ty jsi se tvářila moc jako cizí člověk.
Sasa, a stranger acts like a stranger.
Sašo, cizí člověk se tváří jako cizí člověk.
You need to get my attention somehow.
Musíš něčím upoutat moji pozornost.
I don't know, shout something.
Já nevím, tak třeba něco zakřič.
Fried chicken at a great price.
Smažená kuřata za výhodnou cenu.
Or something like that.
Nebo tak něco.
You know that when I have to lie, I faint.
Teď víš, že když chci lhát, tak omdlívám.
Fine, don't then.
No tak ne.
Then yell.
Tak volej ji.
Overpriced stinky chicken and people are going to run right into that little shop, right.
Předražený smradlavý kuřata a lidi hned do toho krámečku asi poběžej, nebo co.
It's enough if they just take a flyer from me.
Mně stačí, když se ode mě vezmou leták.
To afford decent swimwear, I need to hand out four thousand of them.
Na to, abych sehnala slušný plavky, jich musím rozdat čtyři tisíce.
They pay you ten hellers per flyer?
Ti dávají deset haléřů za leták?
No, one heller.
Ne, halíř.
But for forty crowns you can get nice ones.
Ale za čtyřicet korun už jsou pěkný.
We sure didn't need that school pool.
Ten školní bazén nám byl čert dlužnej.
Mom is thrilled.
Maminka je nadšená.
She already took out the shower.
Už odmontovala sprchu.
But I have to lose five kilos in two weeks to even show up there.
Ale já musím za čtrnáct dní zhubnout pět kilo, abych si tam vůbec mohla ukázat.
You could say, no Iva, you don't need to lose weight.
Můžeš říct, ne Ivo, ty nepotřebuješ zhubnout.
That's what girls do with each other.
Tak si to totiž mezi kamarádkama dělá.
Well.
No.
No, Iva, you don't need to.
Ne, Ivo, ty nepotřebuješ.
Tomas, finally.
Tomáši, no konečně.
What do you look like?
Jak to vypadáte?
Don't tell me the movers didn't show up for Gott either.
Neříkejte mi, že ani Gottovi ti stěhováci nepřijeli.
Can you believe it.
No představte si to.
Same thing as with Petr Janda.
Stejný jako tehdy u Petra Jandy.
I hope you're not mad that I arranged that party for you.
Doufám, že se na mě nezlobíte, že jsem vám tu oslavu dohodila.
Not at all, we managed in the end.
Ale vůbec ne, nakonec jsme to zvládli.
Peta Kotvald drove the van, Jitka Zelenkova packed the glass, and the boys from the Czechoslovak Television bar made a human chain.
Peťa Kotvald hnal dodávku, Jitka Zelenková zabalila sklo a kluci z Baratu Československé televize udělali lidský řetěz.
Was Michal David there too?
A byl tam i Michal David?
He was.
Byl.
He sang for us while we worked.
Ten nám k tomu zpíval.
That must have been lovely.
To muselo být krásné.
The nation's elite.
Elita národa.
And how selflessly they help each other.
A jak si dovede nezištně navzájem pomoci.
And in the end it even paid off for me.
A nakonec se mi to ještě vyplatilo.
Karel gave me a voucher for Chez Blimbles.
Karel mi za to dal poukázku do Chez Blimbles.
Chez Blimbles.
Chez Blimbles.
They have amazing foie gras there.
Tam mají senzační husí játra.
We were going to celebrate Pesticide-Free Day there with Zoran, but he thought it was too expensive.
Měli jsme tam se Zoranem oslavit Den bez pesticidů, ale nakonec se mu to tam zdálo příliš drahé.
Even Zoran?
I Zoranovi?
Well, how about that.
No to se podívejme.
And guess who'll be dining there — Ozzak.
A vidíte, bude tam večeřet Ozzák.
What's that supposed to mean?
To je co?
Ozzak?
Ozzák?
Well, Iva didn't want to go, so who else was I supposed to take.
No, Iva nechtěla, tak koho jinýho jsem měl vzít.
Of course, who else would you take but Ozzak.
Jistě, koho jiného byste měl vzít než Ozzáka.
Marcelka, actually I wanted to ask you something.
Marcelko, vlastně jsem vás chtěl poprosit.
Could you explain to him the basics of table etiquette?
Neměla byste mu nějak vysvětlit základy stolování?
I'm a bit lost with that stuff too.
Tak já v tom taky trochu plavu.
Of course.
Samozřejmě.
Who else should help you?
Kdo jiný by vám měl pomoci?
You're a gem.
Jste zlatá.
Mind if I grab a bite?
Já si zobnu, můžu?
Iva's dieting, so tonight's dinner won't be worth much.
Iva hubne, takže dneska večeře nebude stát za nic.
I'm off then.
Tak já běžím.
It doesn't smell great, but you could still eat healthier.
To nevoní to, ale stejně bys mohl jíst zdravějc.
Any bread?
Chleba je?
Bread is full of carbs.
Chleba je plnej sacharidů.
I worked hard all day, I'm entitled to some nutrients.
Já jsem celý den dřel a mám nárok na živiny.
Were you chopping down trees?
Ty jsi kácel nějaký stromy?
I was carrying pianos all day.
Celý den jsem nosil klavíry.
Just try it.
Tak to ochutnej.
Maybe you'll be surprised.
Třeba budeš překvapenej.
Salt makes you retain water.
Sůl zadržuje v těle vodu.
I'm going to Chez Blimbles with Ozzak the day after tomorrow.
Půjdu s Ozzákem do Chez Blimbles pozítří.
We'll stuff ourselves for a week ahead.
Nadlábneme se tam na týden dopředu.
Fine.
Fajn.
In a week she'll be switching from cabbage to rutabaga.
Za týden budu přecházet z kapusty na tuřín.
Hey, bro.
Zdar, brácha.
Hi, Lusko.
Ahoj, Luško.
Hey.
Čau.
You're awfully cheerful for a cabbage night.
Jsi už nějaký veselej na to, že je kapusta.
I'm already full.
Jdi, já jsem najedenej.
What did you have?
Co jsi měl?
Apples.
Jabka.
See, you're eating healthy.
No vidíš, stravuješ se zdravě.
Wait.
Moment.
You ate apples?
Ty jsi jedl jabka?
Yeah, I tried them.
No, zkusil jsem to.
We're talking about the round things that grow on trees.
Bavíme se o takovým tom kulatým, co roste na stromech.
Come on, I know what an apple is.
No dovol, co pak nevím, co je to jabko.
I picked them from the apple tree behind the building.
Jsem si je natrhal na jabloní za barákem.
Just listen.
No jen, Louň.
That thing behind the building is a birch tree.
To za barákem je bříza.
Well, from that then.
No tak na ní.
A birch tree where the super hangs suet balls for the tits.
Bříza, na kterou správcová věší lojový koule pro sýkorky.
Dear God.
Pane Bože.
If the super saw you.
Jestli tě správcová viděla.
She did, she even waved at me.
No viděla, ještě na mě mávala.
I'm going over there.
Jdu tam.
Your pusher.
Váš puser.
Why again?
Proč zas?
For God's sake, you ate the birds' food and you're asking stupid questions?
Ježišmarja, sežral jsi ptákům žrádlo a ještě se tak blbě ptáš?
You think they take it that hard?
Myslíš, že si to tak berou?
I think you're overthinking this.
Já myslím, že si to moc bereš.
Yeah?
Jo?
How would you feel if you found out someone might have starved because of you?
Jak by bylo tobě, kdyby ses dozvěděla, že možná kvůli tobě někdo umřel hlady?
Look, if something's just lying around, why not take it?
Hele, když se někde něco válí, proč to nevzít?
Did the birds have their name on it?
Měli to ty ptáci podepsaný?
Well, no.
No to ne.
Did it say "property of birds, do not touch"?
Měli tam napsaný majetek ptáků nesahat?
You know, they can't write.
Víš, oni neumějí psát.
Fine, but some of them can talk.
Dobře, ale některý umějí mluvit.
Then you should've posted one as a guard, it could've told you.
Tak jsi tam měl jednoho postavit, ten ti to mohl říct.
I still think they're mad at me.
Stejně si myslím, že jsou na mě nakrknutý.
A pigeon pooped on me on the way here.
Když jsem šel sem, posral mě holub.
Don't be crazy.
A nebuď blázen.
When we run out of salt or bread, I send Lexa with a bag to the feeder and we've never had any trouble with deer.
Nám když dojde sůl nebo chleba, tak pošlu Lexu s pytlem do krmítka a v životě jsme žádný problémy s jelenama neměli.
Because they can't come after you.
No protože za tebou nepřijdou.
Have you ever seen one in Prague?
Viděl jsi někdy v Praze aspoň jednoho?
What?
Co?
A deer!
No jelena!
But there are billions of birds.
Ale ptáků je tu miliarda.
But birds are
Vždyť ptáci jsou
What could they do to you?
Co by ti mohli udělat?
Tiny, have you ever seen an ostrich?
Mrňavý, viděl jsi někdy pštrosa?
Sure, but it can't fly, you can outrun it.
No jo, ale ten nelítá, tomu utečeš.
Ozzak!
Ozzáku!
I sorted it out for you, but it's the last time.
Tak jsem ti to vyžehlil, ale bylo to naposled.
Awesome!
Super!
Did you talk to the birds?
Ty jsi mluvil s ptákama?
What are you on about?
Co to meleš?
I talked to the super.
Se správcovou jsem mluvil.
How could I talk to birds?
Jak bych mohl mluvit s ptákama?
Some of them can talk.
No některý umějí.
What's wrong with him?
Kdo mu je?
A pigeon pooped on him.
Posral ho holub.
No, I didn't talk to the birds.
Ne, s ptákama jsem nemluvil.
Then you haven't sorted out anything.
Tak to jsi nevyžehlil vůbec nic.
Look, if you keep this up, you're not going anywhere with me tomorrow.
Hele, jestli jim budeš tvrdít, tak se mnou zítra nikam nepůjdeš.
Here's the menu.
Tady je jídelní lístek.
Lexa printed it from the internet.
Lexa mi to vytiskl z internetu.
Pick something, the voucher has a limit.
Něco si vyber, ten poukaz má limit.
I'll add it up so we stay within budget.
Já to pak spočtu, to abysme se vešli.
Then why not go to a bigger place?
No tak nepůjdem do nějaký větší?
Shut up and pick.
Sklapni a vybírej.
Wow, I wish I were your sister.
Teda, já bych chtěla být tvoje ségra.
You take such good care of your family.
Ty se tak hezky staráš o rodinu.
Nobody takes care of me.
O mě se nikdo nestará.
Simona, I'm going with my brother so we don't starve.
Simona, já jdu s bráchou, abysme netrpěli hlady.
Just pick something.
Vybírej si.
Is capon a fish?
Kapoun je ryba, jo?
No, poultry.
Ne, drůbež.
What's poultry?
Co je drůbež?
Birds.
Ptáci.
Then we're not going.
Tak to nejdem.
Why not?
Proč zas?
Why?
Proč?
They're already mad at me, should I provoke them more?
Už takhle jsou na mě naštvaný, ještě je budu provokovat, ne?
Good call.
Dobře děláš.
Bro, you're nuts, and you stop encouraging him.
Brácha, ty jsi cvok a ty ho v tom nepodporuj.
Is woodcock a mushroom?
Sluka je houba?
Also a bird.
Taky pták.
For God's sake, do they have anything besides birds?
Herrgott, mají tam něco jinýho než ptáky?
How about truffles.
Tak tady třeba lanýže.
Truffles aren't birds, right?
Lanýže nejsou ptáci, jo?
It's a mushroom.
To je houba.
I don't eat mushrooms.
Houby nejím.
Then try frog legs.
Tak zkus žabí stehýnka.
So I feel sick again?
Aby mi zase bylo blbno, co?
Taking you anywhere is impossible.
Hele, tebe taky někam vzít.
Well, if they have beer.
No tak jestli tam mají pivo.
Are you crazy?
Zbláznil ses?
In a French restaurant?
Ve francouzský restauraci?
They only have wine.
Tam mají jenom víno.
Then what have we been talking about this whole time?
Tak o čem se tady celou dobu bavíme?
Look, I don't care, I'll gladly go alone.
Hele, mě to je jedno, já klidně půjdu sám.
Fine, I'll have a sausage at the train station.
Klidně, já si dám v nádražce klobásu.
But you'd be bored there.
Ale to by ses tam nudil.
I'll eat anything, I don't need beer, and I know how to be grateful.
A já sním všecko, pivo nepotřebuju a umím být vděčná.
Simona, you're acting like you can't afford food.
Simono, ty se chováš, jako kdybyste neměli na jídlo.
Well.
Víte.
I hope you're not bringing back licked-off lumps like last time.
Doufám, že nepřineseš samý olízaný houdy jako posledně.
There was no salt, just chestnuts.
Sůl tam nebyla, jenom kaštany.
Well then take them, let Sasa try baking them.
No tak to odnes, Saša ať to zkusí upíct.
Here you go, mom.
Došli, mami.
Bye.
Nashle.
Not everyone can afford to eat at Chez Blimbles.
Každej si nemůže dovolit jít na gábl do Chez Blimbles.
Then pick something and come with me.
Tak si něco vyber a pojď tam se mnou.
What was that?
Co to bylo?
You said the restaurant was French, right?
Říkal jsi přece, že ta hospoda je francouzská, ne?
...vegetarians protested in Prague against inadequate conditions in poultry factory farming.
...vegetariáni demonstrovali v Praze proti nevyhovujícím podmínkám při chovu drůbeže ve velkochovech.
Iva, you have to hide me!
Ivo, musíš mě schovat!
What is it?
Co je?
Quick, I think I was handing flyers to the wrong people.
Rychle, asi jsem nabízela letáky špatným lidem.
What?
Co?
They seemed so nice, saying how much they loved chickens.
No oni vypadali tak sympaticky, jak říkali, že mají rádi kuřata.
Yeah.
No.
So I tried giving them flyers and they started yelling that meat is murder, called me a fascist, and started chasing me.
Tak jsem jim zkusila dát pár letáků a oni začali křičet, že maso je vražda, že jsem fašista a začali mě honit.
Relax, they're not going to follow you home.
Klid, ve Guši tě domů sledovat nebudou.
Sis, some weird people came looking for you and wanted to see what we eat.
Ségra, doma tě hledali nějaký divný lidi a chtěli vidět, co jíme.
So I showed them the chestnuts and they left.
No tak jsem jim ukázal kaštany a zase odešli.
You eat chestnuts?
Víte kaštany?
Only sometimes.
Jenom někdy.
They're not very good.
Nejsou moc dobrý.
What am I supposed to do with these flyers now?
Co teď mám dělat s těmi letáky?
You have to be careful who you give them to.
Musíš si dávat bacha, komu je strkáš.
Iva, the boss said if I don't hand out enough, they'll put me in a costume.
Ivo, šéf říkal, že jestli jich rozdám málo, tak mě přeřadí na práci v kostýmu.
And how many have you handed out?
A kolik jsi jich rozdala?
Will you take one?
Vezmeš si?
Sure.
No jo.
Make it two.
Tak dva.
No, I already have one.
No, já už mám.
Well, maybe the costume will be nice.
No, třeba ten kostým bude pěkný.
Good morning.
Dobré ráno.
Morning.
Dobré.
Where's Ozzak?
Kde je Ozzák?
I think he went to the zoo.
Myslím, že jel do zoo.
Why on earth?
A proč sakra?
He came in, asked who the king of birds is, and when we told him it's the eagle, he went to see it.
Přišel, zeptal se, kdo je král ptáků, a když se mu řeklo, že orel, jel za ním.
And he took money from the register for rabbits.
A z pokladny si vzal peníze na králíky.
This can't be happening.
To snad není možné tohle.
He's completely lost it.
Jemu normálně přeskočilo.
He's afraid of birds and because of that he won't even go to Chez Blimbles.
Bojí se ptáků a kvůli tomu ani nejde do Chez Blimbles.
So?
Takže?
So I'm taking Simona.
Takže beru Simonu.
What are you doing?
Co to děláte?
After yesterday I went to music therapy.
Po včerejšku jsem šla na muzikoterapii.
To better express my emotions.
Že bych dokázala lépe vyjádřit své emoce.
The teacher said when something upsets me, I should hum a song of instinct and I'll feel better.
Učitel říkal, že když se mě někdo dotkne, mám zabroukovat píseň instinktů a bude mi líp.
Did I upset you?
Já jsem se vás dotkl?
I was the one who arranged that party for Gott.
Tu oslavu Gottovi jsem vám dohodila já.
Was there much interest?
A jaký o ni byl zájem?
Gabina Partysova bought a bikini for it.
Gabina Partyšová si kvůli tomu koupila bikiny.
And now someone else gets the foie gras.
A teď si dá husí játýrka někdo jiný.
Jesus, well then I apologize.
Ježiš, no tak to já se vám omlouvám.
What was that?
To bylo co?
Same thing!
Totéž!
Alright, alright, I'll try to explain to Simona somehow, hopefully she'll understand that I'm going to dinner with you.
Dobře, dobře, tak já zkusím Simoně nějak vysvětlit, snad to pochopí, že na tu večeři půjdu s vámi.
Was that a song of joy?
To byla píseň radosti?
A song of cautious optimism.
Píseň střízlivého očekávání.
Hi.
Rejden.
Well, Mr. Ozzak, what happened to you?
Teda, pane Ozzáku, co se vám stalo?
I had a disagreement with an eagle.
Nepohodl jsem se s orlem.
Eagles are dangerous.
Orlové jsou nebezpeční.
And supposedly a king.
A prej král.
I thought it would have some dignity and not attack me the moment I touched the enclosure.
Myslel jsem, že bude mít nějakou důstojnost a nevrhne se na mě hned, jak jsem se dotkl toho výběhu.
Did you have a white flag?
No a měl jste bílou vlajku?
No, but the rabbit was white.
Ne, ale ten králík byl bílej.
I don't understand these birds.
Já těm ptákům nerozumím.
Ever since I saw that movie, I watch out for them too.
Co jsem viděl ten film, tak se taky na ně radši dávám bacha.
Movie?
Film?
It's called The Birds.
Jmenuje se to Ptáci.
Mom played it for us when my sister wanted to buy a parakeet.
Mamka nám ho pustila, když si ségra chtěla koupit andulku.
I'd like to see that.
To by mě zajímalo.
I'll bring it tonight.
Tak já vám ho večer přinesu.
Yeah.
Jo.
No!
Ne!
I'm not eating fried chicken even for you.
Já nebudu jíst smažený kuřata ani kvůli tobě.
If I don't bring in a single customer, I'm getting put in the costume.
Jestli nepřivedu ani jednoho zákazníka, tak půjdu do kostýmu.
No, I'm on a diet.
Ne, držím dietu.
Bye.
Čau.
I wouldn't eat chicken either, it's dangerous.
Kuřata bych taky nejedl, je to nebezpečný.
Now that surprises me.
No to mě překvapuješ.
I know what I know.
Vím svý.
So you'll have cabbage with me?
Takže si se mnou dáš kapustu?
I don't eat mushrooms.
Houby nejím.
It's not a mushroom, it's what we had yesterday.
Ale to není houba, to je to, co jsme měli včera.
Oh, then also no.
Aha, tak to taky ne.
Simona?
Simono?
Yeah?
No?
I need to talk to you about dinner at the French restaurant.
Potřeboval bych s tebou probrat tu večeři v té francouzské restauraci.
Look, this is a bit awkward, but hopefully you won't mind.
Hele, je mi to teda trochu blbý, ale snad by ti to ani tak nevadilo.
Quack?
Kvá?
Never mind.
Vlastně nic.
I think it could be a nice evening.
No já myslím, že to může být hezký večer.
Marcelka, please stop drumming that song of doubt, or we'll never get anywhere.
Marcelko, prosím vás, přestaňte neustále bubnovat tu píseň pochybností, jinak se nikam nedostaneme.
The voucher is for two people with three courses.
Poukaz na večeři je pro dvě osoby o třech chodech.
So if each of us gives up...
Takže, když se každý z nás vzdá...
Never.
Nikdy.
Sorry, reflex.
Pardon, reflex.
So if each of us gives up one course, we'll all still eat.
Takže, když se každý z nás vzdá jednoho chodu, stejně se všichni najíme.
The portions at Chez Blimbles aren't big.
Porce v Chez Blimbles nejsou veliké.
Let's each get a salmon sandwich from the deli across the street.
No tak si dáme naproti v lahůdkách každý chlebíček s lososem.
What do you say?
Co říkáte?
Mr. Grant.
Mr. Grant.
Wait, I meant everyone pays for themselves.
Ne moment, já jsem myslel každý za své.
What was that?
To bylo co?
Don't even ask.
Ani se neptejte.
Fine, I'll skip the soup.
Tak já si teda nedám polévku.
And I'll skip dessert.
A já dezert.
Wait, that means I won't have a main course?
Moment, to znamená, že já nebudu mít hlavní chod?
Then have two sandwiches?
Tak si dáš ty chlebíčky dva?
That doesn't seem fair.
No to mi nepřipadá spravedlivé.
Stop it!
Nechte toho!
Karel gave me that dinner voucher, not some women.
Tu poukázku na večeři mi dal Karel, ne ženský.
I feel like staying home with cabbage.
Mám chuť zůstat doma u kapusty.
Hey, take it easy.
Čau, klídek.
Hey.
Čau.
Ivuska, is there at least bread with the cabbage?
Ivuško, máme k té kapustě aspoň chleba?
There won't be cabbage.
Kapusta nebude.
No?
Ne?
Too many carbs.
Je v ní moc sacharidů.
But I have sprouts and green juice.
Ale mám klíčky a zelenej džus.
I'll be at the deli.
Jsem na vás v lahůdkách.
Hey.
Čau.
Is that Mr. Ozzak?
Je to pan Ozzák?
Uncle's home.
Strejk dom.
So, Lexa?
Tak co, Lexo?
You got it?
Máš to?
What are you wearing?
Co to máš na sobě?
This is protection against birds, so they don't peck my eyes out.
No to mám proti ptákům, aby mi nevyklovali oči.
Great.
Super.
What will you be doing?
Co tu budete dělat?
We'll be watching a movie about birds.
No budeme se dívat na film o ptákách.
Yeah, I don't need to be here for that.
Jo, tak u toho bejt nemusím.
When Sasa comes to show off her costume, send her to me.
Jo, až se Saša přijde předvést v tom kostýmu, tak ji za mnou pošlete.
Sure.
Jo.
Uncle?
Strejdo?
Yeah?
No?
Are you going to watch the movie in that?
Ty v tom budeš koukat na ten film?
I was planning to.
Myslel jsem, že jo.
I see.
Aha.
Let's see these Birds then.
Tak se ukažte, Ptáci.
Bonjour.
Bonjour.
Can you speak Czech?
Můžete česky?
We'd like a table for three.
Chtěli bychom stůl pro tři.
Do you have a reservation?
Máte rezervaci?
We have a voucher.
Máme poukaz.
Our VIP voucher?
Náš VIP poukaz?
Yes.
Ano.
May I see it?
Mohu ho vidět?
Of course.
Jistě.
You already looked there.
Tam už jste hledal.
You're kidding.
To mi neříkej.
For real.
No fakt.
And the people hadn't done anything to them.
A ty lidi jim vůbec nic neudělali.
I think they must have done something terrible.
Já myslím, že jim museli udělat něco hrozného.
Worse than eating their food?
Horšího, než že by jim sežrali žrádlo?
No, no.
Ne, ne.
Really nothing at all.
Fakt vůbec nic.
Look, they might fly in here too.
Koukej, stačí, že sem taky vlítnou.
Then we won't open.
Tak jim neotevřem.
In the room.
V pokoji.
Thank you.
Děkuju.
What are you staring at?
No co se to díváte?
At the birds, not at you.
Na ptáky, a ne na vás.
Jesus, I think I'm getting anxious.
Ježíš, mám z toho asi tužbu.
Unbelievable.
Není možný.
Oh, there are a lot of people here tonight, aren't there?
Oh, il y a beaucoup de monde ici ce soir, non?
What on earth is that?
Co to proboha je?
Mr. Gott?
Pan Gott?
No.
Ne.
Any messages?
A co vzkazy?
Afraid not.
Tak bohužel.
Stay calm.
Klid.
It's not the first time.
Není to poprvý.
The fire department is on their way.
A hasiči už jsou na cestě.
Hold on!
Držíte se!
What a view!
To je výhled!
I can see the super on the toilet.
Vidím správcovou na hajzlu.
Don't move or that branch will break.
Nehýbejte se, nebo se ta větev utrhne.
The boss said people would notice me in this costume, but not that they'd jump out the window.
Šéf říkal, že si mě lidi kvůli tomu kostýmu všimnou, ale ne, že přede mnou vyskočí z okna.
It's not the costume's fault.
Ten kostým za to nemůže.
Yes it is, it's terrifying now.
Ale může, teď je hrozný.
Iva, how many times do I have to tell you not to scare Ozzak.
Ivo, kolikrát ti mám říkat, že toho Ozzáka nemáš děsit.
Now he's up in a tree again.
Teď už je zase na stromě.
That's Sasa.
To je Saša.
Hey, Sasa.
Dobrý, Sašo.
I'll put the payment through your window.
Do okna ti strčím splátku.
Sure, whatever.
No jo, porad.
Good evening, Mr. Pacovsky.
Dobrý večer, pane Pacovský.
Lexa, you're up there too?
Lexo, ty seš tam taky?
Hi, Mom.
Ahoj, mami.
Right, when Ozzak jumps out the window, you have to follow, huh?
No jo, když Ozzák vyskočí z okna, tak ty musíš taky, co?
Dear God, what a day.
Pane Bože, to je zase den.
The fire department is on their way.
Hasiči už jsou na cestě.
Let's have a snack while we wait, shall we?
Tak se zatím spravíme chuť, ne?
You're still hungry after dinner?
Vy máte po té večeři ještě hlad?
We ended up skipping that fancy restaurant.
Nakonec jsme se na tu stovkovou hospodu vykašlali.
Yeah.
No.
I'm furious.
Zlost mám, jo?
I'll have some too then.
Tak já si vezmu taky.
Birds don't talk.
Ptáci nemluví.
Wait, so the diet is over?
Počkej, tak je zhubnutí konec?
Some things take priority.
To se sluší tak.
What am I supposed to do?
A co mám dělat?
He's simply afraid of birds.
Prostě se bojí ptáků.
But this is the most bizarre thing he could come up with.
Ale tohle je to nejbizarnější, co ho mohlo napadnout.
He believes that if he looks like them, they'll leave him alone.
Věří, že když bude vypadat jako oni, tak ho nechají na pokoji.